<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analyst on Just Numbers &amp; Things</title>
    <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/categories/analyst/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analyst on Just Numbers &amp; Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>

	<atom:link href="http://justnumbersandthings.com/categories/analyst/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


    <item>
      <title>Importing a CSV into a database using DBeaver</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2018-06-12-dbeaver-import-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2018-06-12-dbeaver-import-csv/</guid>
      <description>0) Install DBeaver You can find installation instructions here
1) Create a folder to be used as your CSV Database mkdir ~/desktop/csvs
Place the CSV you want to load into this folder
2) Create a CSV database connection In the menubar select Database &amp;gt; Create a New Connection &amp;amp; from the list of drivers select Flat files(CSV) &amp;gt; CSV/DBF
Set the path of the connection to the folder you created earlier (the JDBC URL will auto-populate)</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title> Connecting to Hive with DBeaver using Kerberos Authentication</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-05-06-dbeaver-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-05-06-dbeaver-hive/</guid>
      <description>0) Install DBeaver You can find installation instructions here
1) Download the latest drivers You can find the latest drivers on the Cloudera website
2) Create a folder mkdir ~/.dbeaver-drivers/cloudera-hive/
3) Extract driver jars and move to folder 4) Create New Driver in DBeaver  Navigate to Database &amp;gt; Driver Manager &amp;gt; New Add all the files from ~/.dbeaver-drivers/cloudera-hive/ Driver name: Hive-Cloudera (for labeling only) Class name: com.cloudera.hive.jdbc41.HS2Driver (at the time of this writing) Default port: 10000 URL template: jdbc:hive2://{host}:{port}/{database};AuthMech=1;KrbRealm=FOO.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Installing DBeaver on a Mac</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-03-26-dbeaver-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 21:35:50 -0800</pubDate>

      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-03-26-dbeaver-mac/</guid>
      <description>0) What is DBeaver? Quite simply DBeaver is the best multi-database SQL IDE that I&amp;rsquo;ve used. It supports every JDBC connection that I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown at it and has advanced features for some of the more popular databases such as Mysql &amp;amp; Postgres. Many thanks to serge-rider for creating such an awesome tool.
1) Install Java First we need to install java which can be easily done as follows:
brew cask install java  Note: Previous versions of this article instructed an installation of the cask jce-unlimited-strength-policy but that has been removed as its contents have been incorporated into the cask java with the release of 9.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>