<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tinkerer on Just Numbers &amp; Things</title>
    <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/categories/tinkerer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tinkerer on Just Numbers &amp; Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://justnumbersandthings.com/categories/tinkerer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2018-03-23-hugo-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2018-03-23-hugo-migration/</guid>
      <description>What was I using before Previously I was using Pelican a static site generator written in Python. Personally I&amp;rsquo;m a huge Python fan which led me to search out Pelican rather than go with a more popular solution such as Jekyll.
Why Change As it turns out if you aren&amp;rsquo;t going to be modifying the static site generator in anyway you don&amp;rsquo;t need to concern yourself with the language that it is written in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS 10.13.2 EGPU Adventures</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-12-28-egpu-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-12-28-egpu-adventures/</guid>
      <description>1) What is an EGPU &amp;amp; when did Apple start supporting them? The acronym EGPU stands for external GPU. Until recently they were relatively niche however, with the release of thunderbolt3 they have begun to gain traction. At WWDC17 Apple announced that they would be fully supported in High Sierra sometime during the spring of 2018. This news was welcomed at egpu.io where a community of capable individuals have been trail blazing EGPUs on macOS prior to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Tableau&#39;s Document API</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-06-04-improving-tableaus-document-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-06-04-improving-tableaus-document-api/</guid>
      <description>1) What is Tableau&amp;rsquo;s Document API? With the release of Tableau 10, Tableau released a python utility called the Tableau Document API (or TDA for short). TDA allows users to easily programmatically modify tableau workbooks. Modifying tableau workbooks without using Tableau Desktop was possible before as tableau files .twb are actually just xml files. However, manually editing the xml of .twb files could easily result in a corrupted workbook. Fortunately with the release of this tool it is now much less risky to modify workbooks without using Tableau Desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog With Pelican</title>
      <link>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-03-03-pelican-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justnumbersandthings.com/post/2017-03-03-pelican-intro/</guid>
      <description>Update 2018-03-18: I&amp;rsquo;ve since moved to Hugo This is my first blog post using Pelican and Markdown. A lot of the content below is to be used as reference mostly for myself and any others who are exploring using Python3, Pelican, &amp;amp; Markdown to create a blog.
How to get up and running
mkvirtualenv personal_blog pip install pelican pip install markdown pip install fabric3 pip install ghp-import pip install webassets npm install less -g cd Dropbox/projects/python/personal_blog/ git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>